## Yasir Rafiq

yasirrafiq33@gmail.com

+923224701887

ST#1B inayyat bagh baghbanpura Lahore, Pakistan Fullstack MEAN,MERN,MEVN, Javascript Engineer

#### Senior Software Engineer

Senior Software Engineer offering a strong foundation in software engineering and programming principles across multiple platforms. Quickly learn and master new technologies, successful working in both team and self-directed settings. Experienced in MEAN, MERN and MEVN stack, developing, testing and debugging code, designing interfaces, designing Databases and implementing. Enthusiastic about learning new technologies and skills for better solutions and algorithms.

## Work Experience

Senior Software Engineer - Turing.com (Dec/2021 - Present)

Senior Software Engineer - Venturedive (Dec/2019 - 2021)

Senior Software Engineer - Coeus Solutions GMBH (Feb/2017 - 2019)

Software Engineer - Dashroad (Novatore solutions) (2015 - 2017)

### Education

- BS Information Technology (4 years' degree) Punjab University College Of Information & Technology (2011 - 2015)
- Pre-Engineering Sciences Govt. Islamia College Railway Road Lahore, Pakistan (2009 2011)
- Matriculation Truman school systems (2007 2009)

# **Projects**

- Turing.com
  - It's a platform to shortlist different engineers across the world for silicon valley based remote jobs. I am working with their internal team as a senior software engineer. The two main products, currently I am working with in team.
    - Experimentation Framework: We have cloned open source project GrowthBook, customized it as per our requirements. The A/B feature flagging, experiments, metrics and stats engine are the basic functionalities of the experimentation framework.
    - Centralized logging API and Platform: Created google api for collecting

logs from different products, store them on gcp and sink to BQ and centralize storage. Generate different dashboard reports based on that BQ data.

#### Apexchat

Widget based application that provides chat services to different companies or portals. The widget lands on any web portal for chat communication.

#### Childrenplace

Shopify for some specific countries and brands. I worked there as a front-end engineer using Reactjs as the main library.

#### Covetme

Your voice is more powerful within your group of friends than any other outside noise. This application works for brands as a shout-out using influencers (social media accounts) and paying them in rewards. I am working on this project as Team Lead and developing on both the front end, back end side.

#### Ekomi Voe

Developed front -end module for ekomi voe to know about employees interest, mood and reviews about the company. Voice of employee (VOE) is self descriptive.

#### getBravio.io

Rewards based on OKRs, interactive web interface with strong back-end architecture. Defined OKRs against activities.

#### Dashroad

Developed front-end module for dash-road to track and report driving behavior of a driver to monitor vehicle movement, location, and performance to improve safety and fuel usage etc.

# **Projects**

- ReactJs VueJs -NestJS -Graphql AngularJs -NodeJS -BackboneJs -Javascript
- -Angular MongoDB -JQuery -CSS -HTML -APIs -Jira -github -Bitbucket